Narrator: Kathy
Kathy: So, the best advice I’ve ever been given…
Well, in my early career I remember I’d been having
– I’d been having trouble with a more junior colleague in our department,
and I wasn’t particularly senior – important – at that time where I was working,
but I did need to get him to do something that he really didn’t want to do and he kept avoiding it.
And I didn’t want to upset him by insisting on it, and I really just couldn’t get anywhere with it,
and now I think my boss could see what was going on.
She was quite a… quite a perceptive person.
Anyway, she said one evening she could give me a lift home,
and she just asked me point blank what the matter was,
and I was so stressed by that point that I just told her the problem I was having with this colleague,
and she said: ‘Well, if you’re sure you’re right about this, and I think you are, then go ahead.’
And I said I was just really worried that we wouldn’t be able to get on
– me and this colleague – anymore.
And she said, ‘Well, I think you’re right about that, but the best advice I can give you is:
he’s your colleague, and not your friend,
and just remember that it’s not important that everybody likes you.’
I was quite shocked, but in fact it was really good advice and,
in difficult situations through my working life, I’ve remembered and, and followed that advice.
Narrator: Emma
Emma: In terms of the best piece of advice I’ve ever been given,
it’s not something that was given to me personally,
but I’ve been listening to a lot of podcasts recently, about body positivity,
and confidence, and being healthy, and all that kind of stuff,
and I’m not sure who it was but one of the podcasters basically said, you know,
no one’s actually looking at you – everyone’s very self-conscious.
When you put on swimwear, when you’re in your summer clothes,
you think that you’re going to walk out onto a beach and everyone’s just going to turn around and stare at you,
but the reality is, everyone’s just far more concerned about themselves than they are about you.
I think that’s quite a good thing to live by, and I do try to think like that.
Narrator: Cecile
Cecile: The only thing I can think of off the top of my head is
when I was with my sister shopping and we went into a department store.
I think we were looking for a present for someone,
and I fell in love with some really expensive shoes, and they weren’t even dressy shoes,
they were just trainers – very nice ones, I just love them – and my sister said to me,
‘I think you should get them. They’re so “you” and you’ll wear them loads.’
Anyway, she convinced me, and I’ve been wearing them for the last three years, day-in, day-out.
If you use that system of dividing the price of something by how often you wear it,
they sort of worked out cheap, I think.